<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<sop>

  <metadata>
    <id>SOP-MKT-001</id>
    <title>Marketing Campaign Cross-Team Communication Protocol</title>
    <version>1.0</version>
    <effective_date>[DATE]</effective_date>
    <review_date>[DATE + 1 YEAR]</review_date>
    <owner>Marketing Manager</owner>
    <approved_by>[Name / Title]</approved_by>
    <classification>Confidential – Internal Use Only</classification>
    <applies_to>All marketing campaigns</applies_to>
  </metadata>

  <section id="1" title="Purpose">
    <body>
      This SOP defines the mandatory process for notifying and preparing the Payments Team and
      Customer Service (CS) Team whenever the Marketing Team launches or schedules a promotional
      campaign. Its goals are to ensure operational readiness, minimise risk exposure, detect
      bonus abuse early, and deliver a consistent player experience across all touchpoints.
    </body>
  </section>

  <section id="2" title="Scope">
    <body>Applies to all marketing campaigns including but not limited to:</body>
    <items>
      <item>Welcome and sign-up bonuses</item>
      <item>Reload and deposit-match promotions</item>
      <item>Free spins, free bets, and no-deposit offers</item>
      <item>Loyalty, VIP, and tiered reward campaigns</item>
      <item>Seasonal or event-based promotions (e.g. tournaments, jackpots)</item>
      <item>Referral and affiliate-driven campaigns</item>
      <item>Retargeting and re-engagement campaigns</item>
    </items>
    <teams_in_scope>
      <team>Marketing</team>
      <team>Payments</team>
      <team>Customer Service</team>
    </teams_in_scope>
  </section>

  <section id="3" title="Roles and Responsibilities">
    <role id="marketing_manager">
      <name>Marketing Manager</name>
      <responsibilities>
        <item>Owns the campaign brief and initiates cross-team notification</item>
        <item>Ensures the Campaign Brief Pack is complete and distributed on time</item>
        <item>Monitors for bonus abuse patterns and coordinates a cross-team response</item>
        <item>Holds authority to pause or terminate the campaign if abuse or risk thresholds are breached</item>
        <item>Chairs pre-launch sign-off and post-campaign debrief meetings</item>
      </responsibilities>
    </role>
    <role id="payments_lead">
      <name>Payments Team Lead</name>
      <responsibilities>
        <item>Receives briefing and configures deposit rules for the campaign period</item>
        <item>Briefs Payments agents on campaign mechanics and escalation path</item>
        <item>Oversees real-time transaction monitoring throughout the campaign</item>
        <item>Escalates anomalies and fraud patterns to the Marketing Manager immediately</item>
        <item>Compiles post-campaign transaction report</item>
      </responsibilities>
    </role>
    <role id="payments_agents">
      <name>Payments Agents</name>
      <responsibilities>
        <item>Apply campaign-specific deposit rules correctly</item>
        <item>Monitor higher-value transactions in real time</item>
        <item>Log and escalate any flagged accounts or suspicious patterns to the Payments Lead</item>
      </responsibilities>
    </role>
    <role id="cs_lead">
      <name>Customer Service Team Lead</name>
      <responsibilities>
        <item>Receives briefing and trains CS agents on promotion FAQs before launch</item>
        <item>Ensures consistent and accurate query resolution across the team</item>
        <item>Escalates unresolved complaints and abuse flags to the Marketing Manager</item>
        <item>Compiles post-campaign CS query summary</item>
      </responsibilities>
    </role>
    <role id="cs_agents">
      <name>Customer Service Agents</name>
      <responsibilities>
        <item>Answer all player queries on the promotion accurately and consistently</item>
        <item>Follow approved FAQ scripts; never speculate outside approved content</item>
        <item>Flag suspected player abuse patterns to the CS Lead immediately</item>
        <item>Escalate complaints, mis-sell allegations, and regulatory threats promptly</item>
      </responsibilities>
    </role>
    <role id="crm_bi">
      <name>CRM / BI Analyst</name>
      <responsibilities>
        <item>Provides live reporting dashboards for the duration of the campaign</item>
        <item>Flags unusual behavioural or financial metrics to the Marketing Manager</item>
      </responsibilities>
    </role>
  </section>

  <section id="4" title="Notification and Briefing Timeline">
    <body>
      All briefings must be completed before the campaign goes live. The following minimum lead
      times are mandatory.
    </body>
    <timeline>
      <milestone timeframe="5+ working days before launch" owner="Marketing Manager">
        Marketing shares the Campaign Brief Pack with the Payments Lead and CS Lead
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="3 working days before launch" owner="Payments Lead">
        Payments Lead confirms deposit thresholds, monitoring plan, and abuse detection setup
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="3 working days before launch" owner="CS Lead">
        CS Lead distributes the FAQ document and runs the team briefing session
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="1 working day before launch" owner="Marketing Manager">
        Final confirmation call and sign-off across all three teams
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="Launch day" owner="All Leads">
        Payments monitoring activated; CS agents ready; Marketing confirms go-live
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="24 hours post-launch" owner="All Leads">
        Initial performance and incident check-in meeting
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="72 hours post-launch" owner="Marketing Manager">
        Full campaign health review; escalate any unresolved issues
      </milestone>
      <milestone timeframe="Campaign end + 2 days" owner="Marketing Manager">
        Post-campaign debrief; SOP improvement notes recorded
      </milestone>
    </timeline>
  </section>

  <section id="5" title="Campaign Brief Pack (Mandatory Document)">
    <body>
      Marketing must produce and distribute a Campaign Brief Pack for every campaign.
      The pack must include all of the following sections.
    </body>

    <subsection id="5.1" title="General Campaign Information">
      <items>
        <item>Campaign name and unique reference ID</item>
        <item>Campaign type (bonus, free spins, referral, reload, etc.)</item>
        <item>Start date, end date, and active hours with time zone</item>
        <item>Targeted player segments (new, existing, VIP, geography)</item>
        <item>Channels used (email, SMS, push notification, paid social, affiliate)</item>
        <item>Estimated reach and expected uplift in player activity</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="5.2" title="Promotion Mechanics">
      <items>
        <item>Full Terms and Conditions — plain-English summary and legal version</item>
        <item>Trigger conditions (minimum deposit, opt-in required, promo code)</item>
        <item>Bonus value, structure, and award timing</item>
        <item>Wagering requirements and game restrictions</item>
        <item>Maximum withdrawal from bonus winnings</item>
        <item>Expiry periods for bonus credits and free spins</item>
        <item>Exclusions (payment methods, countries, player segments)</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="5.3" title="Player-Facing Content">
      <items>
        <item>Approved FAQs and scripted answers for CS agents</item>
        <item>Links to landing page, banner creative, and email template</item>
        <item>Key messaging and tone guidance (what to say and what not to say)</item>
        <item>Escalation wording for players unhappy with the promotion</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="5.4" title="Abuse Risk Parameters (set by Marketing)">
      <items>
        <item>Defined bonus abuse indicators for this campaign (e.g. structuring deposits, rapid withdrawal post-bonus)</item>
        <item>Maximum number of promotional accounts per household or device</item>
        <item>Payment methods excluded from the promotion</item>
        <item>Velocity thresholds that trigger a manual review</item>
        <item>Escalation contact within Marketing for confirmed abuse cases</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section id="6" title="Payments Team – Specific Responsibilities">

    <subsection id="6.1" title="Pre-Launch Actions">
      <items>
        <item>Review Campaign Brief Pack and confirm deposit bonus thresholds</item>
        <item>Configure or verify payment system rules for the promotion period</item>
        <item>Set up real-time monitoring alerts based on abuse risk parameters provided by Marketing</item>
        <item>Brief all Payments agents on campaign mechanics and escalation path</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="6.2" title="During the Campaign – Transaction Monitoring">
      <body>
        The Payments Team is specifically responsible for monitoring higher-value deposit
        activity throughout the campaign period.
      </body>
      <items>
        <item>Track unusual spikes in deposit volume or average deposit value against baseline</item>
        <item>Identify players making multiple deposits at or near bonus trigger thresholds (structuring behaviour)</item>
        <item>Flag accounts depositing via multiple payment methods in a short window</item>
        <item>Monitor for rapid bonus-to-withdrawal patterns</item>
        <item>Report all flagged activity to the Marketing Manager without delay</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="6.3" title="Escalation Triggers – Payments">
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Transaction volumes exceed [X]% of baseline within a 2-hour window</trigger>
        <action>Notify Marketing Manager immediately via phone and #campaigns-live channel</action>
      </escalation_rule>
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Single player depositing above [defined threshold]</trigger>
        <action>Log in Incident Register and notify Marketing Manager within 30 minutes</action>
      </escalation_rule>
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Confirmed or suspected multi-accounting or promotional abuse</trigger>
        <action>Notify Marketing Manager immediately; Marketing Manager decides on campaign action</action>
      </escalation_rule>
      <notes>
        <item>All escalations logged in the Incident Register within 30 minutes of detection</item>
        <item>Marketing Manager owns the abuse investigation and any decisions to restrict accounts or pause the campaign</item>
      </notes>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="6.4" title="Post-Campaign – Payments">
      <items>
        <item>Compile transaction volume report for the full campaign period</item>
        <item>Document all flagged and investigated accounts</item>
        <item>Submit summary findings to Marketing Manager within 2 business days of campaign end</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section id="7" title="Customer Service Team – Specific Responsibilities">

    <subsection id="7.1" title="Pre-Launch Actions">
      <items>
        <item>CS Lead reviews Campaign Brief Pack and raises any ambiguities with Marketing before launch</item>
        <item>CS Lead drafts or approves the player-facing FAQ document (template from Marketing)</item>
        <item>Mandatory team briefing session held at least 1 working day before launch</item>
        <item>All CS agents complete a knowledge check on campaign mechanics</item>
        <item>Escalation contact for complex queries confirmed and circulated to the team</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="7.2" title="During the Campaign – Query Handling">
      <body>CS agents must be equipped to handle all promotion-related player queries, including:</body>
      <items>
        <item>How to qualify (eligibility, opt-in steps, promo codes)</item>
        <item>When and how the bonus or free spins will be credited</item>
        <item>Wagering requirements and which games count towards them</item>
        <item>Withdrawal conditions and maximum bonus winnings</item>
        <item>What to do if a bonus has not appeared as expected</item>
        <item>Promotion expiry and consequences of not using the bonus in time</item>
        <item>Why a player may have been excluded from the promotion</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="7.3" title="Tone and Accuracy Standards">
      <golden_rule>
        Agents must never speculate or provide information not in the approved FAQ.
        If unsure, confirm with the CS Lead before responding. Incorrect information
        given to players about promotions constitutes an operational and reputational risk.
      </golden_rule>
      <items>
        <item>All responses must align with approved campaign wording</item>
        <item>Agents must not make exceptions to campaign T&amp;Cs without authorisation from the CS Lead</item>
        <item>Any player complaint about the fairness of a promotion must be escalated to the CS Lead</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="7.4" title="Abuse Indicators – CS Observations">
      <body>
        CS agents are often the first point of contact with players attempting to exploit a
        promotion. Agents must flag the following behaviours to the CS Lead immediately, who
        will escalate to the Marketing Manager:
      </body>
      <items>
        <item>Player enquiring about how to use multiple accounts to access the promotion</item>
        <item>Player asking whether they can transfer a bonus to another account</item>
        <item>Player with a pattern of claiming bonuses and immediately requesting withdrawals</item>
        <item>Multiple contacts from the same device, IP, or household regarding the same promotion</item>
        <item>Player attempting to circumvent an exclusion from the promotion</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="7.5" title="Escalation Triggers – CS">
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Player has not received bonus after meeting all stated conditions</trigger>
        <action>Escalate to Payments Lead if unresolved within 24 hours</action>
      </escalation_rule>
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Player alleges the promotion was mis-sold or misleading</trigger>
        <action>Escalate to CS Lead and Marketing Manager</action>
      </escalation_rule>
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Player threatens a regulatory complaint</trigger>
        <action>Escalate to CS Lead and Marketing Manager immediately; document in full</action>
      </escalation_rule>
      <escalation_rule>
        <trigger>Promotion-related contacts exceed [X] per hour</trigger>
        <action>CS Lead to notify Marketing Manager; assess whether FAQ update is required</action>
      </escalation_rule>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="7.6" title="Post-Campaign – CS">
      <items>
        <item>CS Lead compiles summary of promotion-related queries: volume, top issues, resolution rate</item>
        <item>Flag any recurring ambiguities in campaign T&amp;Cs for future improvement</item>
        <item>Submit CS summary report to Marketing Manager within 2 business days of campaign end</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section id="8" title="Bonus Abuse Management (Marketing-Led)">
    <body>
      The Marketing Team owns bonus abuse detection and response for all campaigns.
      Payments and CS feed intelligence upward; Marketing investigates and acts.
    </body>

    <subsection id="8.1" title="Abuse Detection Sources">
      <items>
        <item>Payments Team: transaction monitoring alerts and flagged account reports</item>
        <item>CS Team: player behaviour observations reported during live support interactions</item>
        <item>CRM / BI dashboards: unusual conversion spikes, deposit patterns, and withdrawal velocity</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="8.2" title="Common Abuse Patterns to Monitor">
      <items>
        <item>Multiple accounts per player (multi-accounting) claiming the same bonus</item>
        <item>Structured deposits designed to trigger bonus thresholds repeatedly</item>
        <item>Immediate or near-immediate withdrawal following bonus clearance</item>
        <item>Coordinated group abuse (gnoming) across linked accounts</item>
        <item>Use of excluded payment methods to circumvent promotion restrictions</item>
        <item>Arbitrage play — targeting low house-edge games to meet wagering requirements</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>

    <subsection id="8.3" title="Marketing Response Actions">
      <items>
        <item>Review flagged accounts against campaign eligibility criteria</item>
        <item>Void bonuses for accounts in confirmed breach of T&amp;Cs</item>
        <item>Restrict future promotional eligibility for confirmed abusers</item>
        <item>Pause or modify campaign parameters if systemic abuse is detected</item>
        <item>Document all abuse cases in the Abuse Log for pattern analysis</item>
        <item>Update campaign T&amp;Cs and abuse risk parameters for future campaigns based on findings</item>
      </items>
    </subsection>
  </section>

  <section id="9" title="Communication Channels and Tools">
    <channels>
      <channel>
        <type>Campaign Brief Pack distribution</type>
        <method>Email to all leads plus shared drive folder (link in email)</method>
      </channel>
      <channel>
        <type>Pre-launch briefing meetings</type>
        <method>Video call — calendar invite sent by Marketing Manager</method>
      </channel>
      <channel>
        <type>Live campaign updates</type>
        <method>Dedicated Slack or Teams channel: #campaigns-live</method>
      </channel>
      <channel>
        <type>Urgent escalations during campaign</type>
        <method>Phone call to Marketing Manager plus message in #campaigns-live</method>
      </channel>
      <channel>
        <type>Post-campaign reports</type>
        <method>Email to Marketing Manager plus upload to shared drive</method>
      </channel>
      <channel>
        <type>Incident and abuse logging</type>
        <method>Incident Register and Abuse Log (shared documents — links in brief pack)</method>
      </channel>
    </channels>
  </section>

  <section id="10" title="Incident Management">
    <body>
      Any operational issue during a campaign — technical fault, unusual player behaviour,
      abuse pattern, or significant query spike — must be treated as a campaign incident.
    </body>
    <steps>
      <step number="1">Detecting team (Payments or CS) logs the incident in the Incident Register immediately</step>
      <step number="2">Team Lead notifies Marketing Manager via phone and #campaigns-live within 30 minutes</step>
      <step number="3">Marketing Manager convenes an urgent cross-team call within 1 hour of notification</step>
      <step number="4">Decision made to continue, modify, or pause the campaign based on severity</step>
      <step number="5">All decisions and actions documented in the Incident Register</step>
      <step number="6">Post-incident review held within 3 business days; learnings fed back into this SOP</step>
    </steps>
  </section>

  <section id="11" title="Post-Campaign Debrief">
    <body>
      A debrief meeting must be held within 5 working days of campaign close.
      Attendees: Marketing Manager, Payments Lead, CS Lead.
    </body>
    <agenda_items>
      <item>Campaign performance vs. targets (impressions, conversions, deposit uplift)</item>
      <item>Payments review: transaction volumes, flagged accounts, confirmed abuse cases</item>
      <item>CS review: query volume, top issues, resolution rate, player sentiment</item>
      <item>Abuse review: patterns detected, actions taken, T&amp;C gaps identified</item>
      <item>Lessons learned and recommended SOP updates</item>
    </agenda_items>
    <note>
      Debrief notes must be saved to the shared campaign archive folder. Agreed process
      improvements must be reflected in this SOP within 10 working days.
    </note>
  </section>

  <section id="12" title="Document Control and Version History">
    <review_cycle>
      This SOP must be reviewed and re-approved every 12 months, or immediately following
      any significant campaign incident. Owner: Marketing Manager.
    </review_cycle>
    <version_history>
      <entry>
        <version>1.0</version>
        <date>[DATE]</date>
        <summary>Initial version. Marketing-led abuse management. No separate compliance role.</summary>
      </entry>
    </version_history>
  </section>

  <sign_off>
    <approver role="Marketing Manager">
      <name>[Name]</name>
      <date>[Date]</date>
    </approver>
    <approver role="Payments Team Lead">
      <name>[Name]</name>
      <date>[Date]</date>
    </approver>
    <approver role="Customer Service Team Lead">
      <name>[Name]</name>
      <date>[Date]</date>
    </approver>
  </sign_off>

</sop>
